{
  "reference_number": "13059",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a goal to reach net zero emissions by the second half of the century and the Climate Change Commission advises on the specific target for the Government to set later",
      "answer_index": 11,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Long-Lived Gases and Stabilised Short-Lived Gases - Long-lived gases to net zero by 2050 while also stabilising short-lived gases",
      "answer_index": 12,
      "notes": "Why would you reduce gases that only need to be stabilised to control warming, if we are truly worried about our environment then\n we need to consider all environments including our social environment, the one were we can still feed our people. I think a portion of\n\n our government is taking for granted our agricultural industry to satisfy an agenda that discounts NZ position as not only a country\n that can feed its people but has a responsibility to feed others as it has for generations."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "I don't fully trust other countries to have genuine carbon credits to sell, not sure of the regulations."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "We do not know the future, we have got things wrong before. What if carbon zero doesn't improve our environment and reduce\n\n severe weather events? We need to adapt to the real goal of protecting our environment."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "I would add regional considerations, to allow a region to adjust without causing hardship or loss of jobs in a given region"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "I think the list of desirable but not essential should be essential also"
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Needs to be region specific, impower the local community so we can achieve goals that are best for all of us. Treating the whole\n\ncountry the same will not work."
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I think the minister discussed a lot of emotive and opinionated propoganda that is not helpful to this discussion, he has geniune\nconcerns about climate change which I share but we are actually targeting carbon emmissions in this disucussion not climate change\n\nand I am not sure he defined this in his excutive summary. I do not believe that short lived carbon emmissions such as methane have\nan effect on global warming if they are stabilised but they will be considered the biggest issue in NZ from what the minister has\n\nwritten. Applying more blame on the primary sector will not help change our emmissions in this country, change is going to have to\nbe from everyone and by attacking one industry he is giving an out for others. This is not helpful to achieving our goal of contolling\nclimate change and if this is the leadership of the carbon zero I have concerns about the final outcome that the minister will achieve."
    }
  ]
}
